Guide to the School of Medicine, Yale University, Student Examinations
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
School of Medicine, Yale University, student examinations
1875-1905
RU 456
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
6.5
The records consist of annual examinations and matriculation examinations written by students enrolled in the Yale School of Medicine.
Yale University. School of Medicine
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 27-F (YRG 27-F), Student records of the Yale School of Medicine.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Arrangement
The materials are arranged by accession.
Biographical / Historical
Elliott Dunlap Smith: B.A. Harvard 1913, LL.B., 1916; Professor Industrial Engineering, Yale, 1928-1932, Professor Industrial Relations, 1932-1938, Professor Economics, 1938-1946, asst. to the President, 1942-1943.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of annual examinations and matriculation examinations written by students enrolled in the Yale School of Medicine.
College students; Medical students; Medicine -- Study and teaching; Yale University -- Examinations; Yale University -- Students; Yale University. School of Medicine
- Student examinations, 1875-1887; Accession 1981-A-021
  - 1875, June
    - Blake, Charles L. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Foster, John P.C. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Howard, William (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Hunger, Elisha (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Sanford, Issac R. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Smith, Bayard T. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - 1876, February-June
    - Questions (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Drew, Francis H. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Dwight, Edward S. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Gorham, Frank (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Hadley, Frederick H. (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Henderson, George H. (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Huntington, Samuel H. (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Johnson, Laban H. (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Smith, Herman B. (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Sommerville, Beverly R. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Warner, Egbert R. (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Welch, Edward H. (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - 1877, February-June
    - Deane, Wallace H. (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Farnham, C.C. (non-g.) (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Hall, Franklin W. (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Michaelian, Gregory (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Osborne, Curtiss H. (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Welch, William C. (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - 1878, January-June
    - Fleischner, Henry (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Gaylord, E.E. (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Gaylord, John F. (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Griswold, C.S. (failed) (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Henriques, John P. (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Lindsley, Charles P. (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Little, Herbert W. (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Lord, W.A. (failed) (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Mailhouse, Max (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Reilly, Jas J. (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Sargent, D.A. (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Smith, Walter J. (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - Wechsler, H. (failed) (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - 1879, January-June
    - Auger, George J. (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - Baker, Seath R. (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - Barker, James C. (Box 5, Folder 40-41)
    - Flint, Eli P. (Box 5, Folder 42)
    - Gibson, Robert J. (Box 5, Folder 43)
    - Gorham, Robert J. (Box 6, Folder 44)
    - Graves, William B. (Box 6, Folder 45)
    - Jewett, Thomas B. (Box 6, Folder 46)
    - Kelsey, H.J. (Box 6, Folder 47)
    - Leighton, Atton W. (Box 6, Folder 48)
    - Miller, William S. (Box 6, Folder 49)
    - Moody, C.W. (Box 6, Folder 50)
    - Parker, J.R. (Box 6, Folder 51)
    - Robbins, G.O. (failed) (Box 6, Folder 52)
    - Roberts, Charles T. (Box 7, Folder 53)
    - Sedgwick, Wm. J. (Box 7, Folder 54)
    - Surridge, Charles G. (Box 7, Folder 55)
    - Thacker, James K. (Box 7, Folder 56)
    - Tyler, Nathan P. (Box 7, Folder 57)
    - Wakeman, William J. (Box 7, Folder 58)
  - 1880, June
    - Allan, W.H. (Box 7, Folder 59)
    - Calef, J.F. (Box 7, Folder 60)
    - Currier, Andrew F. (Box 7, Folder 61)
    - Curtis, Henry H. (Box 7, Folder 62)
    - Doutteil, Henry (Box 8, Folder 63)
    - Howland, Charles H. (Box 8, Folder 64)
    - McGowan, Charles E. (Box 8, Folder 65)
    - Roberts, Edward K. (Box 8, Folder 66)
    - Russell, William S. (Box 8, Folder 67)
    - Vinal, Leonidas C. (Box 8, Folder 68)
  - 1881, June
    - Brinley, William H. (Box 8, Folder 69)
    - Bush, George M. (Box 8, Folder 70)
    - Dana, Charles W. (Box 8, Folder 71)
    - Hawkes, William W. (Box 9, Folder 72)
    - Lea, Walter Lee (Box 9, Folder 73)
    - Park, Charles E. (Box 9, Folder 74)
    - Richardson, Dwight A. (Box 9, Folder 75)
    - Stetson, James E. (Box 9, Folder 76)
    - White, Caryl F.S. (Box 9, Folder 77)
    - Whiting, Walter C. (Box 9, Folder 78)
    - Miscellaneous Tests (Box 9, Folder 79-80)
  - 1882 (Box 10, Folder 81-83)
    General note
    exams after 1882 either lack names or coherent order
  - 1883 (Box 10, Folder 84-87)
  - 1884 (Box 11, Folder 88-93)
  - 1884-1885 (Box 12, Folder 94-99)
  - 1885-1886 (Box 13, Folder 100-104)
  - 1886-1887 (Box 14, Folder 105-109)
- Student examinations, 1894-1905; Accession 1981-A-022
  - Annual Examinations and Matriculation Examinations, 1894-1901, 1902-1905 (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
- Examination papers (photocopy), 1880; Accession 1990-A-112
  Scope and Contents
  Copies of examinations by Loren T. Day, Yale M.D. 1880. Originals are housed at the University of Kansas Medical Center, Department of History and Philosophy of Medicine.
  - Anatomy, 1880 February 7 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - [Chemistry], [1880?] (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - [Clinical Medicine], [1880?] (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Histology and Pathology, 1880 June (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Materia Medici and Therapeutics, 1880 June 18 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - [Obstetrics], [1880?] (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Physiology, 1880 February (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Surgery, 1880 June 22 (Box 1, Folder 8)